eleducation.org 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy | EL Education

At EL Education, we collect and manage user data according to the following Privacy Policy. One of our top priorities is making sure that the information we have about you is protected and secure. We value our relationship with you and are absolutely committed to preserving your privacy.  

This document is part of EL Education's Terms of Service, and by using ELeducation.org, commoncoresuccess.ELeducation.org, commoncoresuccess.ELeducation.org, elcommonground.ning.com and ModelsOfExcellence.ELeducation.org, (individually or collectively the “Website”), you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Service. Please read the Terms of Service in their entirety, and refer to those for definitions and contacts.

Minors and children should not use the Website. By using the Website, you represent that you have the legal capacity to enter into a binding agreement.

EL Education and all of the websites referred to above, are operated from the United States. If you are visiting the Website from outside the United States, you agree to any processing of any personal information you provide us according to this policy.

## 1\. Information we collect

We collect anonymous data from every visitor of the Website to monitor traffic and fix bugs.

We collect personal information of visitors who submit their information via the forms on all of our websites. In order to enable these or any other login based features, social sharing functionality, Google Analytics and other site feedback, we use cookies to store session information for your convenience. You can block or delete cookies and still be able to use our websites. EL Education uses cookies in the following ways:

  * For logging in a user and maintaining the session
  * For allowing the site to determine whether the user's browser is JavaScript capable
  * For Google Analytics
  * For social sharing functionality
  * For providing site feedback

Email: We maintain an internal email list of all persons who have requested information, enrolled in our programs, registered to use EL Commons, made an online payment, or made an online donation. We may use this list to send occasional updates and announcements about EL Education’s programs and resources, or emails of a marketing or soliciting nature. If you do not wish to receive email you may opt out at any time. We process requests to opt out of email communication via email, the link to our email preferences, or SafeUnsubscribe at the bottom of any marketing email. Email requests may be sent to [socialmedia@elschools.org](mailto:socialmedia@elschools.org); these are processed within three business days. Please note that transactional emails may still be sent to you on an as-needed basis.

Post: Persons who submit their postal address with the goal of receiving further information or making a donation may periodically receive postal mail from us. If you do not wish to receive mail, please let us know by sending a request to [development@ELeducation.org](mailto:development@ELeducation.org). Please provide us with your exact name and address and we will be sure your name is removed from our postal mailing list.

Phone: Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers will receive telephone contact from us responding to a request for more information or a transaction, and may also receive unsolicited marketing calls.

## 2\. How we use the data and information

Once your personal information is collected, EL Education may use the information in order to provide you the Website services or to communicate with you about the services or the Website as well as to communicate information and updates regarding events, useful resources, opportunities, etc via email. 

We protect the information you provide by maintaining appropriate security measures in our physical facilities to protect against the misuse of information we have collected from you. All financial information is kept in locked files or electronic files that are password protected. For additional information regarding how EL protects information collected when a purchase, donation, or gift is made, please visit this third-party site: https://www.blackbaud.com/privacy-policy.aspx. 

## 3\. How we share data and information

We do not share personal information you have provided to us without your consent, unless:

  * Doing so is appropriate to carry out your own request;
  * We believe it is needed to enforce our Terms of Service, or that it is legally required;
  * We believe it is needed to detect, prevent or address fraud, security or technical issues;
  * Doing so otherwise protects our property, legal rights or that of others.

The email list we maintain is for internal use only and will not be sold, rented, or exchanged with any other company. No other company will use our email list for their communications.

Post: The postal mailing list we maintain is for internal use only and will not be sold, rented, or exchanged with any other company. No other company will use our postal mailing list for their communications. We would otherwise only share email or postal addresses as required by law.

We do not share any personal information about our prospective partners, schools, teachers, donors, former partners, etc. with anyone external to EL Education without their knowledge and/or permission other than the disclosures listed below, unless required by law.

While we do not share your personal information with third parties, aggregated, anonymized data is periodically transmitted to external services to help us improve the Website and service. We currently use Google Analytics for traffic analysis and SEO optimization.

We also use social buttons provided by services like Twitter, Google+, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Vimeo, YouTube, Instagram and Facebook. Your use of these third party services is entirely optional. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices of these third party services, and you are responsible for reading and understanding those third party services’ privacy policies.

We employ and contract with people and other entities that perform certain tasks on our behalf and who are under our control (our “Agents”). We may need to share personal information with our Agents in order to provide products and services to you. Unless we tell you differently, our Agents do not have any right to use Personal Information or other information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information with our Agents.

We may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, if we, or substantially all of our assets, were acquired, or if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of us or our assets may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

## 4\. Access to your information

If you would like to know exactly what personal information EL Education has collected about you, we will be happy to share it with you. This includes transaction information (e.g., dates on which you made payments, amounts and types of payments), communications you have directed to our staff (e.g., e-mails, customer inquiries), and contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number). Please email [socialmedia@elschools.org](mailto:socialmedia@elschools.org) with a request to review this information.

## 5\. Recourse

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at the above addresses or phone number, or you may contact the DMA's Committee on Ethical Business Practices at [ethics@the-dma.org](mailto:ethics@the-dma.org), or state and local chapters of the Better Business Bureau, state and local consumer protection office, or The Federal Trade Commission by phone at 202-FTC-HELP (202.382.4357) or electronically at: <https://www.ftccomplaintassistant.gov/> (link valid as of January 2009).

## 6\. Changes to the privacy policy

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make major changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Website or sending you an email. A user is bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the Website after such changes have been first posted.

Contact us at [contact@ELeducation.org](mailto:contact@ELeducation.org) if you have any questions regarding this policy.
